

# Javier de la Peña

Software Engineer

## **Personal Info**

**Nationality** Spanish

Based on

Berlin

Phone

0152 06401751

**Email** 

javier.pfayos@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/javier-de-la-pena

#### **Education**

Technician in exploitation of IT Systems I.E.S. Ángel Corella, Madrid

### **Skills**

Java	+10 years
Python, Dart, Kotlin	1 year
Groovy	4 years
Spring	7 years
AWS, Micro-services	6 years
Terraform	4 years
DBs	+10 years
Scrum	8 years

# **Summary**

IT Professional with over 10 years of experience specialized on JVM BE technologies with focus on: micro-service architecture, supporting apps, and application lifecycle.

 ${\rm I}$  am passionate about helping teams and companies to move into faster, more reliable iterations.

# **Experience**

#### **Full stack Developer**

2021-Now Freelance Movie Recommender App

- Development of Rest and SparQL crawler on Kotlin
- Data Analysis using Jupyter Notebooks
- Creation of a multi-platform app using Flutter

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

2017-2020 AUTO1 Group

- Development of libraries for all Java services, such as custom service discovery
- Maintenance of Jenkins CI pipelines and Elastic Search related services
- · Redefinition of services architecture

# **Technical Leader**

2017 bonial.com

- Grow of team ownership on their services and infra
- Move to a fast delivery environment, releasing several times a day our different services

#### **Senior Developer**

2015-2016 bonial.com

- Development of new Java BE solutions for new apps.
- Maintenance of a centralized Groovy API for interaction with mobile front-end apps

2012-2014 Protec Mobile

 Design and development of a Java application for information analysis of their mobile user DB

2012 Startup

• Creation of a multiplatform app with Ruby using RoR

# **Junior Developer**

2009-2010 Alten

- Creation of Coslada town hall's web portal using Java; allowing users to create accounts, spaces, upload media content...
- Implementation of Spring MVC and Hibernate

2008 Alten

 New small Java desktop application using Struts to manage an SQL Server DB

2007-2008 Tecnocom

 Maintenance, bug corrections, and new features for the BBVA Java platform